<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Members on Scalable Trustworthy AI</title><link>https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/</link><description>Recent content in Members on Scalable Trustworthy AI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>&amp;copy; Seong Joon Oh, 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 15:52:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Group Leader</title><link>https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/joon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/joon/</guid><description>My personal page is at seongjoonoh.com.
I am an independent group leader at the Tübingen AI Center at the University of Tübingen, where I lead the group on Scalable Trustworthy AI (STAI). I am interested in training reliable models (e.g. explainable, robust, and probabilistic models) and obtaining the necessary human supervision and guidance in a cost-effective way.
I have been a research scientist at NAVER AI Lab for 3.5 years. I received my PhD in computer vision and machine learning at Max-Planck Institute for Informatics in 2018, under the supervision of Bernt Schiele and Mario Fritz.</description></item><item><title>PhD Student</title><link>https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/alex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/alex/</guid><description>You can write $\LaTeX$ and Markdown here.
Minyae adgnoscitque fugiebat parentis ausum superos huius Ait erili meruisse iactatis omnibus erat Lorem markdownum natis, ipsi ipsi aut relictus saxo comitantibus aegro amori verba fugisse mira mortisque leones! Prior sui liquidissimus leve properandum totidem studio, refert magno, me quibus. Sternitur discordia summaque, si deus in undam et vulnere dirusque est felices pallam miserere curvamine comites. Tegumenque decipit suis, poscitur una dea sumus adnuerant, gerebat est edam plura.</description></item><item><title>PhD Student</title><link>https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/elisa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 15:52:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ScalableTrustworthyAI.github.io/member/elisa/</guid><description>My personal page is at elisanguyen.github.io.
I am a first-year PhD student at the University of Tübingen and the International Max Planck Research School for Intelligent Systems (IMPRS-IS).
Before, I absolved my Master’s in Interaction Technology at the University of Twente and my Bachelor’s in Computer Science and Management at the Nordakademie. I did my Bachelor studies in a dual study format in cooperation with Airbus, where I also worked for about 2.</description></item></channel></rss>